[{"question": "What is the minimum value that can be given to become betrothed?",
"answer": "A woman may be acquired by giving a dinar, which is the value of 96 grains of barley weighed in silver, or anything of equivalent value.",
"source": "Kiddushin 1:1"},
{"question": "If a woman who is an ervah to a man falls to him for yibum, can her rival wives peform yibum?",
"answer": "Yes, the rival wives of an ervah are permitted to perform yibum. If they do not, one of them must perform chalitzah before remarrying.", 
"source":"Kiddushin 1:4"},
{"question": "If the rival wife of an ervah performs chalitzah, is she fit to marry a kohen upon the death of her husband?",
"answer": "No, the rival wife of an ervah who performs chalitzah is treated as if she were a divorcee and is thus prohibited from marrying a kohen.",
"source": "Kiddushin 1:4"},

{"question": "Are the co-wives of an ervah who falls to a man for yibum permitted to perform yibum?", 
"answer": "Yes, the co-wives are permitted to marry or must perform chalitzah before marrying someone else. The ervah does not exempt all other co-wives from the Yibum bond.",
"source":"Yevamot 1:4"},

{"question":"If a woman has done maamar with her yevam, and her sister falls to him for yibum, what is the status of the woman?",
"answer": "The sister is an ervah to the yevam, and thus he cannot perform yibum with her. The woman remains like his wife in every way.",
"source": "Yevamot 3:5"},

{"question":"If a woman awaiting yibum inherits propery, does she have rights to sell or give it away?",
"answer": "Yes, a woman awaiting yibum has the right to sell or give away her inherited property.",
"source": "Yevamot 4:3"},

{"question":"A woman waiting for yibum dies after a brother performed maamar. Who inherits her property?",
"answer":"Maamar is an uncertain arrangement, so melog property must be split between the yavam and the woman's father.",
"source":"Yevamot 4:3"},

{"question":"When has a man accomplished the mitzvah of being fruitful and multiplying?",
"answer":"He must father at lwast two boys.",
"source": "Yevamot 6:6"},


{"question": "In which case may a minor girl perform miun to annul her marriage?",
"answer": "Only after a betrothal, but not after a marriage a girl who was married off by her mother or brothers as a minor can refuse the arrangement.",
"source": "Yevamot 13:1"},
{"question": "Can a minor girl annul her marriage in front of her deceased husband's brother to whom she fell for levirate marriage?",
"answer": "No, the refusal of miun can only be directed to her husband, but not her yavam.",
"source": "Yevamot 13:1"},
{"question": "Must the refusal of miun be done in the present of her husband?",
"answer": "Yes, the miun must specifically be done in the presence of her husband.",
"source": "Yevamot 13:1"},
{"question": "Where can the refusal of miun be done?",
"answer": "The refusal must take place specifically in a court in front of three expert judges.",
"source": "Yevamot 13:1"},
{"question": "How many times can a minor peform the miun refusal?",
"answer": "After she refuses once, the next time she will have to wait until she is of age. Then, she can get married biblically. Otherwise, she can do kiddushin and immediately do nisuin so the new marriage is fixed.",
"source": "Yevamot 13:1"},

{"question": "Can a woman remarry or perform yibum if she is the only witness claiming that her husband died overseas?",
"answer": "Regardless of where the woman and husband were, she is believed. ",
"source": "Yevamot 15:2"},
{"question": "Can a woman recieve her ketubah payment if she is the only witness claiming that her husband died overseas?",
"answer": "Beit Shammai uses a kol vachomer to suggest that allowing the woman to remarry permits her to do something that would otherwise be adultery, a much higher crime than a monetary issue. Ultimately, Beit Shammai convinced Beit Hillel by pointing out that the ketubah document itself states that a woman claims the money when she becomes eligible to remarry.",
"source": "Yevamot 15:3"},
{"question": "If a man has done maamar with a woman and her sister falls to him for yibum, as well, "}

]